A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Officers, RG 3 FA1797
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Speeches and Writings, 1958-2017; 2; 1.33 Cubic Feet 4 containers
  - Hills, Lee, 1958-1998; 2.12
    - Comments by Lee Hills at the Journalism Advisory Committee meeting, 1/30/98, 1998 January 30 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Comments by Lee Hills at the Journalism Advisory Committee Meeting marking the retirement of Burl Osborne, Gene Roberts and Dick Wald from the Knight Foundation Journalism Advisory Committee on 1/30/98 in Miami, Florida. In this speech, Mr. Hills describes how the Journalism Advisory Committee got started and why it is so important.
  - Ibarguen, Alberto, 2005-2016; 2.13
    Remarks re: his new role as KF president and "market-based philanthropy".
    - Untitled Remarks at the Conference of Publishers of Daily Newspapers, Buenos Aires, 2005 July 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 3021
      Speech by KF president-elect Alberto Ibarguen at the offices of the Clarin newspaper in Buenos Aires. Introductory remarks are in Spanish. The text of the speech is in English. The speech emphasized the rapidly changing technology effecting how consumers receive news and opportunities for daily newspapers to capitalize on this technology. He mentions his new role at the Knight Foundation.
    - "Market Based Philanthropy", Community Foundation Silicon Valley, San Jose, CA, 2005 October 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 3346
      Speech by KF president Alberto Ibarguen at the Annual Meeting of the Community Foundation Silicon Valley in San Jose, CA. Mentions his desire for KF to do more "opportunity funding" than "good deeds" funding. Mentions KF funded projects in San Jose and in other communities.
    - Speeches and Writings, 2006 February 9-October 19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 4066
      1. "A Foundation for the Future of Journalism and Communities:, The Harry M. and Edel Y. Ayers Lecture, Anniston, Alabama, 2/9/2006. 2. Notes for Welcome and Introductions - Detroit Community Dinner, 9/11/2006. 3. "Knight-Batten Awards; National Press Club", 9/18/2006. 4 "First Amendment: Appreciating free speech starts with a teacher", Op/ed article in Miami Herald, 9/20/2006. 5. "Delaware Valley Grantmakers Conference" Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania, 10/11/2006. 6. The Akron Roundtable,Akron, OH, 10/19/2006
    - John S. Knight: Spirit of Independence Must Survive, 2006 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 3773
      Editorial appearing in the Miami Herald written by Alberto Ibarguen which is a reflection on the 25th anniversary of Jack Knight's death, an affirmation of the work the Knight Foundation does and a celebration of Knight's giving away its one billionth dollar in charitable contributions, all in the same week as the demise of the Knight Ridder newspaper chain.
    - Speeches and Writings, 2007 June 14-October 14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 4132
      1. Outline of remarks for Naturalization Ceremony, Miami Beach Convention Center, June 14, 2007 at which Ibarguen gave the keynote remarks. 2. Speech at Council on Foundations Conference on Community Foundations and Family Foundations, 9/20/2007, San Francisco, CA. 3. IAPA 63rd General Assembly remarks, Miami, FL, 10/14/2007.
    - Speeches and Writings, 2008 June 12-13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 4334
      1. Knight Arts Partnership Anouncement, Miami, FL, 2/6/2008. 2. Remarks on the Opening of the Newseum, Washington, DC, 418. 3. Speech at the Boston Foundation Media Dinner, June 12, 2008 re: Knight Foundation media innovation strategy. This speech paints the big strategy picture of experimentation and innovation, but it also gives detailed information about KF's four media innovation initiatives. Also includes a cover memo by Marc Fest and an edited version dated 6/10/2008.
    - Speeches and Writings, 2009 January 15-June 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 4431
      1. Speech at the Global Business Forum, University of Miami, 1/15/09; 2. Spring 2009 commencement speech at Miami Dade College, 5/2/2009; 3. Testimony before the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, Hearing on the Future of Journalism, 5/6/09; 4. Opportunity in Times of Change: League of American Orchestras National Conference, Chicago, IL, 6/10/2009.
    - Speeches and Writings, 2010 August 29-September 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 4804
      1. Op-Ed story by Alberto Ibarguen on the Occasion of the Five Year Anniversary of Hurricane Katrina, published in the Sun Herald, Biloxi, MS entitled, "I saw something bigger than the storm; I saw the spirit of the people." 2. Remarks at Community Dinner, Charlotte, NC (in conjunction with Trustee meeting); 3. Q & A re: $24-Million Local-News Effort in the Chronicle of Philanthropy.
    - Speeches and Writings, 2011 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 5549
      1. Staff memo from Liset Huff re: Alberto Ibarguen's moderating a panel discussion with Tim Berners-Lee (WWW foundation) and former British Prime Minister Gordon Brown re: the potential of the Web to play a fundamental role in accelerating social and economic change. The panel was live streamed on the web.
    - Speeches and Writings, 2012 February 21-December 3 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 5546
      1. 2012 Media Learning Seminar. Opening Remarks, 2/21/2012. 2. Community Foundation of South East Michigan Board presentation. Untitled remarks re: digital evolution and relevance, 9/13/2012. 3. Miami Knight Advisory Committee meeting. Remarks, 12/03/2012. Focus was on KF spending on arts projects in Miami.
    - Speeches and Writings, 2013 February 6-November 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 5237
      1. Gathering of Leaders, Miami, FL, Untitled Remarks, 2/6/2013. 2. 2013 Media Learning Seminar, Miami, FL, Welcoming Remarks, 2/9/2013; Dinner Remarks, 2/11/2013 (2 versions); Talking Points for Jonah Lehrer introduction, 2/12/2013. 3. PBS Panel on "Principles of the Internet" with Joi Ito. Talking Points, 5/16/2013. 4. Board of Trustees Meeting/Detroit Community Dinner. Untitled Remarks, 9/8/2013. 5. WLRN Interview with Tom Hudson, Talking Points re: Knight's philosophy on philanthropy and philanthropic funding, 11/08/2013. 6. TIAA-CREF Higher Education Panel, Talking Points, no date [2013]. 7. Center for Effective Philanthropy, Talking Points, 2013.
    - Speeches and Writings, 2014 February-December (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 5547
      1. 2014 Media Learning Seminar, Miami, FL. Opening Remarks, 2/17/2014. 2. Arizona State University Walter Cronkite School of Journalism and Mass Communication, Spring Convocation, May 15, 2014. Remarks re: free speech in the age of the Internet and Innovation and disruption in the news business. 3. Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce. Remarks and introduction of winners of the Alvah Chapman Jr. Award, 9/3/2014. 4. Committee to Protect Journalists Dinner, "The New War on Journalists". Abridged remarks released by KF, 11/26/2014. 5. Knight Arts Challenge Awards, South Florida. Untitled remarks (draft), December 2014. 6. Re-envision our public libraries, 7/19/2014. 7. Chapman Awards honor impact on downtown. Mr. Ibarguen was quoted, "We've arrived at the beginning all over again", as he introduced the inaugural Alva H. Chapman Award of Excellence honoring significant contribution to the development of Miami's original-and renewed-downtown center.
    - Speeches and Writings, 2015 March 5-June 8 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 5548
      Restricted - Open 2026
      1. Philanthropy Miami 2015, Keynote Speech, "Foundations as Change Agents: Leveraging Ideas and Resources", 3/5/2015. 2. PAMM [Perez Art Museum Miami] Community Dinner with Board of Trustees and Community Leaders, 3/8/2015 [2 versions]. 3. Invitation to University of Miami Panel Discussion, "Stories from the Peace Corps", featuring Alberto Ibarguen, Peace Corp volunteer in Venezuela, 1966-1968 and Donna Shalala, 4/22/2015. 4. Rethinking Libraries in the Digital Age, Miami-Dade Library, Miami, FL; Talking Points for Introduction of Guest Speaker, John Palfrey, 6/8/2015. 5. Remarks at Unveiling of Symphony D, Detroit, 11/21/15. 6. Knight Arts Challenge Miami Awards Ceremony Remarks (also includes draft remarks for Victoria Rogers), Miami, 11/30/15. 7. FCC's decision adds voice to 'digital public square', 2/28/2015.
    - Speeches and Writings, 2016 May-December (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 5897
      1. County should be a full partner in funding the arts, by Armando Codina, Adolfo Henriques, and Alberto Ibarguen.
  - Knight, James L. and John S., 1986-2017; 2.14
    - Untitled Comments to Trustees Meeting, 1986 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Knight File Number - 181
      Remarks re: John S. Knight estate, at Philadelphia, PA.
    - Philosophy of the Knight Newspapers, 1969 April-1970 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Knight File Number - 3382
      1. Remarks of John S. Knight before a group of businessmen, April 1969. 2. Remarks to the New York Society of Security analysts, February 24, 1970. 3. Remarks at Annual Meeting of Shareholders of Knight Newspapers, Inc., April 14, 1970.
    - John S. Knight and the Vietnam War, 1967-2017 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Knight File Number - 5918
      Restricted - Open 2028
      Memo from Alberto Ibarguen re: webpage about John S. Knight's columns on the war in Vietnam which was put together by the communications department for a conference in Austin, Texas. Former KF trustee Tom Johnson asked for KF support of the conference. Knight won a Pulitzer Prize for his editorials on the war.
  - Maidenberg, Michael, 2006; 2.15
    - Untitled Remarks to SCANPO (South Carolina Association of Nonprofit Organizations), 2006 March 31 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Knight File Number - 4340
      Handwritten speech by Mike Maidenberg, Community Partners Program, re: KF's response to disasters. Compares Hurricane Katrina with the Grand Forks flood.
  - McPhee, Penny, 1995-1999; 2.16
    - Meet the Donor: Knight Foundation's Arts & Culture Program (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Knight File Number - 182
      Undated remarks re: arts and culture program.
    - Remarks to Grantmakers in the Arts Conference, 1995 January 1 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Knight File Number - 183
      Remarks made in Eureka, CA.
    - Challenges for Arts Organizations and Arts Funders in the 90s, 1995 June 1 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Knight File Number - 184
      Remarks made to the Donors Forum.
    - Remarks to American Symphony Orchestra League, 1995 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Knight File Number - 185
      Remarks on Symphony Initiative.
    - Remarks to the Arts & Business Council, 1995 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Knight File Number - 186
    - Remarks to the National Conference of State Legislators, 1995 July 19 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Knight File Number - 187
      Remarks re: Who should pay for the arts?
    - Remarks to American Federation of Arts, 1995 November 13 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      Knight File Number - 188
      Remarks re: direction of philanthropy in the 90s.
    - Remarks to Vail Valley Institute: Who Should Pay for the Arts?, 1996 June 29 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Knight File Number - 189
      Remarks made in Vail, CO.
    - Remarks to National Museum Services Board, 1997 February 21 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      Knight File Number - 190
      Remarks re: Knight Foundation support for museums, Miami, FL.
    - Speeches and Remarks, 1999 April 6-2001 April 19 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Knight File Number - 4003
      Speeches and Remarks delivered by Penny McPhee, Chief Program Officer, including those to FIU Honors College, Southern Arts Federation, Donor's Forum, Impact II, New American Schools Conference, and HUD. Includes remarks at a book signing for KF trustee, Paul Grogan.
  - Newton, Eric, 2005-2009; 2.17
    - Speeches and Remarks, 2005 July 9-2012 April 16 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      Knight File Number - 5447
      1. Remarks at Sixth Knight Fellowships Reunion and Conference, Stanford University, 7/9/2005; 2. Maynard Suite Opening Remarks at Harvard University, 6/10/2006; 3. The Future of News: College of Communication Honors Convocation, University of Texas, Austin, 4/13/2008; 4. Introducing the Investigative Reporting Initiative, Remarks at the Investigative Reporters and Editors Conference, Baltimore, MD, 6/13/2009; 5. Speech for The Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication's 94th Annual Conference, Denver, CO, 8/3/2010; 6. Speech for World Press Freedom Day, 5/2/2011, Washington, DC; 7. Remarks at Annual Convention of the Investigative Reporters and Editors, 6/11/2011; 8. Remarks at the Opening Panel on The Evolving Profession of Journalism, MEDIA exchanges, Moscow, Russia, 10/3/2011; 9. Speech to Students and Faculty at Arizona State University, 11/14/2011; 10. World Editors Forum, World Association of Newspapers, Vienna, Austria, 10/14/2011; 11. Remarks at Logan Symposium on Investigative Reporting at the University of California at Berkeley, 4/15/2012.
    - "In the digital age, America needs universal, affordable access to broadband", 2009 December 6 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      Knight File Number - 4683
      Editorial, written by Eric Newton, printed in The Miami Herald.
  - Scholl, Dennis, 2013; 2.18
    - Board Presentation, 2013 September 8 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Knight File Number - 5238
      Presentation to the Board of Trustees re: arts funding, especially the launching of a Knight Arts Challenge in St. Paul, MN.
  - Spaniolo, James, 1990-1996; 2.19
    Mr. Spaniolo's speech files contain the text of his remarks to community advisors, community foundations, the Board of Trustees, various luncheons, and a literacy conference.
    - Untitled Remarks at National Philanthropy Day Luncheon, 1990 December 6 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      Knight File Number - 191
    - Untitled Remarks to Florida Foundations, 1991 January 1 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      Knight File Number - 192
      Remarks re: History and purpose of Knight Foundation.
    - Notes on Untitled Remarks to Association of Schools of Journalism and Mass Communication, 1991 December 7 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      Knight File Number - 193
    - Fundraising for the 21st Century, 1992 June 11 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Knight File Number - 194
      Remarks made to National Society of Fundraising Executives Annual Conference.
    - Untitled Remarks to Annual Conference of Florida Association of Nonprofit Organizations, 1993 February 25 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Knight File Number - 195
      Remarks re: relationship between nonprofits and philanthropic foundations.
    - Commencement Address to the University of Miami School of Communication, 1993 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Knight File Number - 196
    - Untitled Remarks in Detroit, 1993 June 14 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Knight File Number - 197
      Remarks re: grants awarded to Detroit area.
    - The Grant Making Process, 1994 March 2 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      Knight File Number - 198
      Remarks to Knight Foundation Advisors Meeting.
    - Untitled Remarks to National Conference on Family Literacy, 1994 May 2 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Knight File Number - 199
      Remarks made in Louisville, KY re: literacy.
    - Untitled Remarks to Greater Wichita Community Foundation Annual Meeting, 1994 July 27 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      Knight File Number - 200
      Remarks made in Wichita, KS.
    - Untitled Remarks to Advisor Meeting, 1996 March 13 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      Knight File Number - 201
      Remarks re: role of community advisors
    - The Role of Foundations in Family Literacy, 1996 April 21 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      Knight File Number - 202
      Remarks to National Family Literacy Conference.
  - Thorman, Damian, 2010; 2.20
    - Speeches and Remarks, 2010 September 29 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      Knight File Number - 5448
      Remarks at National Immigrant Integration Conference, Boston, MA.
  - Zamora, Jose, 2008-2009; 2.21
    - Conference Remarks, 2008-2009 September 2 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Knight File Number - 4328
      Text of remarks given by Jose Zamora, Journalism Program Associate, to the Media Giraffe Conference, Association for Women in Sports Media, Information Needs of Communities Conference, the Austin Forum (announcing that the Knight Center for Journalism in the Americas will refocus its work as a digital media center for Latin American and Caribbean journalism), the EPpy Innovation award, and the Latin American Symposium on Digital Media (in Spanish). Also included are remarks announcing the winners of the Knight International Journalism Award and World Summit remarks.